book-fair.com 2019-12-09

# The Privacy policy of Frankfurter Buchmesse.

This Data Protection and Privacy Statement is to inform you of how Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH collects, manages and processes your personal data that you have provided to us by using our online services on our website : [www.buchmesse.de/en](http://www.buchmesse.de/en) and other related websites, and/or via the functions and contents of these Websites (in the following jointly referred to as “online services” or “website“).

2 – Preliminary information regarding data processing, purpose and legal basis

a – Name of the controller of the data file according to data protection law  
Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH, Frankfurt am Main

b – Managing director and head of data processing  
Juergen Boos

c – Data protection officer of the operation  
Tatjana Walter, [privacy@buchmesse.de](mailto:privacy@buchmesse.de "E-mail privacy@buchmesse.de")

d – Address of the controller of the data file according to data protection law  
Braubachstraße 16, 60311 Frankfurt am Main

e – Purpose of collecting, processing or using the data  
The purpose of the company is organising the Frankfurter Buchmesse, promoting the book and publishing industry by organising book fairs and events abroad, organising congresses, conferences, seminars and similar events on a national and international level, as well as providing information on the book and publishing industry in the form of online databases. All data are collected processed and used solely in pursuit of the declared objectives of the company, in particular for the purpose of:

  * Handling the respective business process
  * market and opinion research
  * enabling the event organiser or a service provider commissioned by the organiser to send out event-related offers
  * providing information before and after the event
  * advertising by mail
  * communicating and updating our portfolio of exhibitors and sharing selected data with individual service providers in fulfilment of a contract.

f - Description of the groups of data subjects and of the associated data or data categories

In pursuit of the purposes mentioned in clause **e** , the following personal data of each of the different groups of individuals is collected, processed and/or used:

g - Recipients or categories of recipients to whom the data can be provided

  * responsible sales and service partners
  * data processers processing personal data on behalf of the controller
  * customers (in fulfilment of the purposes listed under clause e)
  * public agencies (only when overriding legal provisions exist)

h – Retention, vesting and deletion periods:

The data mentioned under clause **f** , will be deleted when the purposes for which they were collected, cease to apply, unless other statutory storage periods are provided by law. The data retained due to statutory storage periods will be deleted upon expiry of the legally prescribed storage periods. To be able to promptly comply with an objection to use personal data that has been collected for advertising purposes, it is necessary to keep the data of persons filing an objection in a block list on a continuous basis.

i - Transfer of data to countries outside of the EU territory

To be able to fulfil the purposes listed under clauses e and f, it is necessary to exchange the data between affiliated companies and responsible sales and service partners within Germany, within the EU and across EU boundaries and such exchange is stipulated by contract. The data of interested parties, exhibitors, visitors, journalists or users of the website is therefore transferred to service partners within Germany, within the EU and across EU boundaries. Data are only transferred to countries outside EU boundaries, if these countries have a corresponding data protection agreement to that effect that this agreement ensures a data protection level similar to that within the EU (e.g. The Privacy Shield Agreement with the United States of America and/or the Binding Corporate Rules).

Some of our websites may have links to the websites of other companies and organisations. In view of the fact that we have no responsibility for these sites, we recommend that you read the information about data protection at these sites in detail.

## Online ordering

When you use our online ordering system, we obtain the data from you that are necessary to process your order and to provide the agreed services. Mandatory data fields that are used to collect the required data are always clearly marked with an asterisk.

To ensure the secure transmission of your data, encrypting systems are used. This means that the communication between your browser and our ordering system is illegible for all other participants on the internet.

## SSL encryption

This website uses SSL encryption for the secure and safe transmission of sensitive contents, e.g. for the registration in My Book Fair. You can recognise an encrypted connection when the address field of the browser changes from "http://" to "https://" and when the padlock icon appears in your browser line. When the SSL encryption is enabled your data cannot be read by third parties during the transmission.

## Cookies

The websites of Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH use cookies. Cookies are text files that are saved and stored on a computer system via an internet browser.

Cookies make it possible to recognise the users of the website. The purpose of this tracking is to facilitate the use of our website for the users. The users can always block cookies by adjusting the browser settings and thus object to the setting of cookies on a permanent basis. In addition, users can use the delete function of the browser or other software programmes to delete cookies that were already installed. This adjustment can be made with all standard internet browsers. However, if you disable the possibility to set cookies, you may not be able to fully use all functions of our website.

## ReCaptcha

To protect our databases and to distinguish human individuals from automated bots, we include [Google LLC](https://about.google/intl/en/)'s reCaptcha service in some online forms. Among other things, Google collects the IP address, sets a cookie and may process other personal data in order to track users across websites. Information on the collection and processing of personal data by Google can be found at [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

## Data logging and log files

With each user access, the website of Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH collects a series of general data and information. This data and information are stored in the log files of the server. The following information can be collected:

(1) the types and versions of browsers used; (2) the operating system used by the system that accesses the website; (3) the website from which an accessing system is directed to our website (so-called referrer); (4) the sub-websites that are called-up by a system accessing our website; (5) the date and time when the access to our website took place; (6) an internet protocol address (IP address); (7) the internet service provider of the accessing system; and (8) other related data and information that are relevant to avert danger in the case of attacks on our information technology systems.

Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH does not use the collected data to identify the respective individual. This information is rather needed (1) to present the contents of our website in a correct way, (2) to optimise the contents of our website as well as the advertising of our website, (3) to ensure the operability of our information technology systems and of the technology of our website on a permanent basis and (4) to provide the law enforcement authorities with the necessary information for prosecution in the case of a cyberattack.

## Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service of Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies” – text files that are stored on your computer in order to enable an analysis of the use of the website that is accessed by you. The cookies-generated information about your use of the website is usually transferred to a Google server in the United States of America and stored there. If the IP anonymization on this website is activated, your IP address will be truncated within member states of the EU or in other states that are party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, your full IP address will be transferred to a Google server in the United States of America and shortened there. Upon request of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to analyse your use of the website to compile reports on website activities to the website operator and to provide other services relating to the use of the website and the internet. The IP address transmitted by your browser via Google Analytics will not be amalgamated with other data of Google. You have the possibility to prevent the storage of cookies by adjusting your browser settings correspondingly; please note that you may not be able to use all the functions of this website if you block the storage of cookies. A further possibility to prevent that the data relating to your use of the website (including their IP address) are collected and processed by Google via the cookie, is to install the browser plugin that can be downloaded at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

You can prevent that your data are captured by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. This click will create an opt-out cookie that enables you to block this website from capturing your data when you visit this website in the future: deactivate Google Analytics

More information on the terms of use and privacy policy can be found on <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html> or on <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en-GB>. On this website, Google Analytics was extended by the code “anonymizeIp” that prevents the anonymised capturing of IP addresses (so-called IP masking).

## Matomo

This website uses the open source web analytics application Matomo. Matomo uses so-called “cookies”. These cookies are text files that are stored on your computer in order to track and analyse your online visits to this website. For this purpose, the cookie-generated data relating to your visit to our website are stored on our server. The IP address is anonymised before the data is stored.

The cookie-generated data of your visit to our website are not disclosed to third parties. You have the possibility to prevent the storage of cookies by adjusting your browser settings correspondingly; please note that you may not be able to use all the functions of this website if you block the storage of cookies. If you want to object to the storage and use of your data, you can disable the storage and use functions by clicking on the following link: [https://piwik.neureuter.de/index.php?module=CoreAdminHome&action=optOut…](https://piwik.neureuter.de/index.php?module=CoreAdminHome&action=optOut&language=en). Clicking on this link will create an opt-out cookie in your browser that blocks the ability of Matomo to store user data. Deleting your cookies will include the deletion of the Matomo opt-out cookie. The opt-out cookie must be reactivated when you visit our website again.

## Google Tag Manager

Our website uses the Google Tag Manager for the provision of all tags (Google Analytics) or banner ads or for other targeting measures.

Tags are small code elements on the website that help measuring the traffic and the visitor behaviour, capturing the impact of online advertising and of social channels, using remarketing and orientation towards target groups and testing and optimising the website.  
Google Tag Manager tracks a series of tags and firing triggers that are defining when these tags are to be applied on the website. When a user visits the website, the current tag configuration is sent to the browser of the user. It contains instructions which tags are to be activated: Click here to read more about how Google Tag Manager works.  
Google Tag Manager is a solution that allows the marketers to manage website tags via a user interface. The tool Tag Manager itself (that implements the tags) is a cookie-free domain. The tool ensures that other tags are activated that will gather data, if necessary. Google Tag Manager does not access these data. Deactivating tags on domain level or cookie level, will implement this deactivation for all tracking tags that are implemented with the Google Tag Manager.

## Google Maps

This website uses Google Maps API for the visual representation of geographical information. Google Maps is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. If you are using Google Maps, Google will also gather, process and use data on the usage of Maps features by visitors accessing the websites. For more detailed information on data processing by Google, please read the Privacy Policy of Google.

## YouTube (Video-Embedding)

Our website uses plugins of YouTube that is operated by Google. The operator of the websites is YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA. If you visit one of our websites that has an integrated YouTube-Plugin, a connection to the servers of YouTube is established. In this process, the YouTube server receives notification which of our pages you have accessed. If you are logged in to your Youtube account, you enable YouTube to associate your browsing behaviour with your personal profile. You can avoid this by logging out of your YouTube-Account. If you wish to read more about how YouTube handles user data, please go to the [privacy policy of YouTube](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-GB&gl=de).

## Facebook

Our pages contain integrated plugins of the social network Facebook that is provided by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, California 94025, USA. You can recognise these Facebook plugins when you see the Facebook logo or the “like-button” on our internet pages. An overview of the Facebook plugins can be viewed here:  <https://developers.facebook.com/products/social-plugins/?locale=en_US>.  
If you visit our website, a direct connection will be established between your browser and the Facebook server via the plugin. Facebook receives notification that you have visited our website with your IP address. If you are logged in to your Facebook account and you click on the “like button”, you can link the contents of our website with your Facebook profile. In this way, Facebook is able to associate your visit to our pages with your user account. Please note that we, as the provider of these websites, are not informed of the contents of the transmitted data and their usage by Facebook. For more information, please refer to the Facebook privacy policy at <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>  
If you wish to block Facebook’s ability to associate your visit to our website with your Facebook user account, please log out of your Facebook user account.

## Facebook Pixels

Our website uses a “Facebook Pixel” from Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, California 94025, USA, that creates a direct link to Facebook servers. Facebook receives the information that you have visited our website. Facebook links this information to your personal Facebook user account, if you have one and if you are logged in. If you visit other websites that use “Facebook Pixels”, that information will also be linked to your Facebook account. We, however, will not be informed of the other websites you visit.

To find out more information on how to protect your privacy on Facebook, please see the Facebook privacy policy <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. The help area of Facebook provides further details on Facebook Pixels and their function: <https://www.facebook.com/business/help/651294705016616>.

## Twitter

Our websites have integrated features of the service Twitter that is provided by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. Using Twitter and the feature “Re-Tweet”, will link the websites visited by you with your Twitter account and announced to other users. During this process, data are also sent to Twitter. Please note that we, as the provider of these websites, are not informed of the contents of the transmitted data and their usage by Twitter. If you wish to read more about Twitter’s privacy policy, please go to <https://twitter.com/privacy>.  
Your privacy settings of your Twitter account can be changed by clicking on this link:  
<https://twitter.com/settings/account>.

## Instagram

Our websites have integrated features of the service provider Instagram that is provided by Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA. If you are logged in to your Instagram account, you are able to link the contents of our websites with your Instagram profile by clicking on the Instagram button. In this way, Instagram is able to associate your visit to our pages with your user account. Please note that we, as the provider of these websites, are not informed of the contents of the transmitted data and their usage by Instagram.  
If you wish to read more about Instagram’s privacy policy, please go to  
<https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875?helpref=page_content>.

## Linkedin

Our website uses features of the network LinkedIn that is provided by LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Each time you access one of our websites containing features of LinkedIn, a connection to the servers of LinkedIn is established. LinkedIn receives notification that you have visited our website with your IP address. If you are logged in to your LinkedIn account, and click on the LinkedIn “recommend button”, LinkedIn will be able to attribute your visit to our internet page to your profile and your user account. Please note that we, as the provider of these internet pages, are not informed of the contents of the transmitted data and their usage by LinkedIn.  
If you wish to read more about LinkedIn’s privacy policy, please go to  
<https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>.

## LinkedIn “Insight Tag”

Our website uses “Insight Tags”, a product of LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland (“LinkedIn”). The “Insight Tag” is a pixel provided by LinkedIn that creates a direct link to LinkedIn servers. LinkedIn receives the information that you have visited our website. LinkedIn connects this information to a unique ID that is either saved on your device as a cookie or provided by your end device (smartphone “Ad ID”) and links it to your LinkedIn account if you are logged in. If you visit other websites that use “Insight Tags”, that information will also be linked to your Facebook account. We, however, will not be informed of the other websites you visit. 

To find out more information on how to protect your privacy on LinkedIn, please see the [LinkedIn privacy policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy).

You can log into LinkedIn and deactivate data collection at any time by following this [link](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/enhanced-advertising).

## Xing

Our website uses features of the network XING that is provided by XING AG, Dammtorstraße 29-32, 20354 Hamburg, Germany. Each time you access one of our websites containing features of XING, a connection to the servers of XING is established. To our knowledge, personal data are not stored when you access XING. In particular, no IP addresses are stored and no usage behaviour is analysed.  
If you want to read more about XING’s privacy policy and the XING share button, please go to <https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy>.

## Shariff

Some of our websites contain integrated components of Shariff. Shariff was developed for the German computer magazine c't and is published via GitHub, Inc.  
The developer of the component is GitHub, Inc. 88 Colin P. Kelly Junior Street, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA.  
We use the privacy-friendly Shariff buttons for our share function.  
Background: The customary social media buttons send the user data to the social media platform each time when the website is accessed and, by doing so, notify the social media networks of the exact browsing behaviour of the user (user tracking). The user does not have to be logged in or be member of the network to be tracked.  
Conversely, a Shariff button, establishes a direct contact between the social network and the visitor not before the user clicks on the share button.  
If you wish to read more about GitHub’s current privacy policy, please go to <https://help.github.com/articles/github-privacy-statement/>.

## SoundCloud

Our websites may contain integrated plugins of the social network SoundCloud that is provided by SoundCloud Limited, Berners House, 47-48 Berners Street, London W1T 3NF, UK. You can recognise the SoundCloud plugins when you see the SoundCloud logo on the websites. If you visit our website, a direct connection will be established between your browser and the SoundCloud server when the plugin has been activated. SoundCloud receives notification that you have visited our website with your IP address. If you are logged in to your SoundCloud user account and click on the “like button” or the “share button”, you can link and/or share the contents of our websites with your SoundCloud profile. This enables SoundCloud to associate your visit to our pages with your user account. Please note that we, as the provider of these websites, are not informed of the contents of the transmitted data and their usage by SoundCloud.  
If you wish to read more about SoundCloud’s privacy policy, please go to <https://soundcloud.com/pages/privacy>  
If you wish to block SoundCloud’s ability to associate your visit to our website with your SoundCloud user account, please log out of your SoundCloud user account before you activate the contents of the SoundCloud plugin.

## Spotify

Our websites have integrated features of the digital music streaming service Spotify. The provider is the Spotify AB, Birger Jarlsgatan 61, 113 56 Stockholm in Sweden. You can recognise the Spotify plugins when you see the green logo on our website. An overview of the Spotify plugins can be viewed at [https://developer.spotify.com](https://developer.spotify.com/).  
If you visit our website, a direct connection can be established via the plugin between your browser and the Spotify server. Spotify receives notification that you have visited our website with your IP address. If you are logged in to your Spotify account and click on the Spotify button, you can link the contents of our website with your Spotify profile. In this way, Spotify is able to associate your visit to our pages with your user account.  
If you wish to read more about Spotify’s privacy policy, please go to  
<https://www.spotify.com/legal/privacy-policy/>.  
If you wish to block Spotify’s ability to associate your visit to our website with your Spotify user account, please log out of your Spotify user account.

## Pinterest

We use the social network Pinterest that is provided by Pinterest, Inc., 808 Brannan St, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA.  
If you click on the Pinterest button, Pinterest receives information that you have accessed the relevant page on our website. If you are logged in to Pinterest, Pinterest can associate your visit to your account. If you click on the Pinterest button, the transmitted data are stored by Pinterest in the USA. If do not wish Pinterest to receive your data, please log out of your Pinterest account.  
For information on the purpose and extent of data capture and the further processing and use of data by Pinterest, please refer to the Pinterest privacy policy at: <https://policy.pinterest.com/en-gb/privacy-policy>.

## Subscribing to and unsubscribing from (objection) our newsletter and information services

The website of Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH offers its visitors the possibility to subscribe to the information and newsletter services of our company. The volume and nature of personal data transmitted during the subscription process to the particular information or newsletter service depends on the input mask you use.  
Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH informs its customers and business partners about the offers of the company in regular intervals by means of information and newsletter services. The information and newsletter services of our company can generally be received by the interested parties only if (1) they have a valid e-mail account and (2) they have registered for information or newsletter services. We rely on the “double opt-in” process. For legal reasons, a confirmation is sent to the e-mail address that was entered by the person registering for the first time for the information or newsletter service. This confirmation e-mail is sent out to confirm that the owner of the e-mail address, as the data subject, has authorised the receipt of the information and/or newsletter service.  
If you register for the information and/or newsletter services, we will also store the IP address that the internet service provider (ISP) has assigned to the computer system that was used by you at the time of the registration, including the date and the time of the log-in. It is necessary to collect these data to be able to track any possible abuse of your e-mail address at a later point of time and thus serves the legal protection of those responsible for the processing of the data.  
The personal data gathered during the subscription of the information and newsletter services are used only for providing our informations and newsletter services. Furthermore, subscribers of information and newsletter services can be notified by e-mail if this should be necessary for the operation of the information and/or newsletter service or if a registration is required, e.g. in the case of changes to the information and newsletter services or changes of the technology. The personal data that is gathered within the scope of the information and newsletter services will not be disclosed to third parties. The data subject may at any time cancel the subscription to our information and newsletter services. He or she may at any time withdraw the consent to the storage of personal data that was given for the purpose of using the information and newsletter services. Each information and newsletter service offers a link specifically for the withdrawal of the consent.

## Newsletter-Tracking

The information and newsletter services offered by Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH contain so-called tracking pixels. A tracking pixel is a miniature graphic that is embedded in e-mails that are sent in the HTML format and it permits log file recording and log file analysis. This enables the statistical interpretation of the success or failure of online marketing campaigns. By means of the embedded tracking pixel, Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH can identify if an e-mail was opened by a user and when it was opened and which of the links contained in the e-mail were accessed by the user.  
The data gathered by means of these tracking pixels that are contained in the information and newsletter services are stored and analysed by us in order to optimise the mailings and to better adapt the content of future information and newsletter services to the preferences of the client. These personal data are not conveyed to third parties. The data subjects may at any time withdraw the consent that they have given separately by means of the “double opt-in” process. Following the revocation, these personal data are deleted. Unsubscribing from the information and newsletter services will be treated automatically as revocation by Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH.

Possibilities to raise objections

  * Any data subject has the possibility to object to the use of his or her data for advertising purposes. Please send your objection to [privacy@buchmesse.de](mailto:privacy@buchmesse.de "E-mail privacy@buchmesse.de") or to: Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH, Datenschutzbeauftragte, Braubachstr. 16, 60311 Frankfurt am Main.
  * Each data subject has the right to object to the processing of his or her personal data, unless the storage of data is a legal obligation in connection with the business processes. Please send your objection in writing to [privacy@buchmesse.de](mailto:privacy@buchmesse.de "E-mail privacy@buchmesse.de") or to: Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH, Datenschutzbeauftragte, Braubachstr. 16, 60311 Frankfurt am Main.

In addition, each individual (data subject) has the following rights:

  * the right to be informed if and what kind of the individual’s personal data are collected and retained by us;
  * the right to make a request for immediate rectification and/or completion if personal data are incorrect or incomplete and the right to receive a supplementary explanation;
  * the right to make a request for erasure of the personal data;
  * the right to make a request for restriction of processing of the data;
  * the right to obtain his or her personal data in a structured, conventional and machine-readable format.

Please send your request in writing to [privacy@buchmesse.de](mailto:privacy@buchmesse.de "E-mail privacy@buchmesse.de") or to: Frankfurter Buchmesse GmbH, Datenschutzbeauftragte, Braubachstr. 16, 60311 Frankfurt am Main, Germany.

  * In addition, each data subject whose personal data are subject to processing has the right to an effective judicial remedy before a court or to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

Last updated: November 2019
